Register to The E. Robert Schmitz Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Correspondence, Series I; 4.2 linear feet (10 boxes)
  - General Correspondence, I.A
    - Clauzel, Alice and Alfred de, 1926 June 2; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Cohen, Pauline, 1932 July 18; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 52)
      From E. Robert Schmitz
    - Collett, Mary
      See: Earle, Rosa M.
    - Columbia Artists Bureau, Inc., 1936 May-Sep. (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Columbia Broadcasting System, Inc. (Box 3, Folder 53)
      1936-1946. -- 8 items from CBS
      1936-1946. -- 5 items from E. Robert Schmitz
    - Columbia Records Inc.
      See: VIII.A. FINANCIAL AND LEGAL MATERIAL. Miscellaneous financial items
    - Columbia School of Music, 1919 Jan.-Feb.; 2 items. (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Comité Artistique de Saigon
      See: Mathieu, Edgar
    - Composers' Music Corporation, 1923 June 5; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 53)
      Photocopy - for original see also: Whithorne, Emerson
    - Composers Press, Inc.
      See: Haubiel, Charles
    - Concerts Pasdeloup (Box 3, Folder 54)
      1920-1927. -- 3 items from Concerts Pasdeloup to E. Robert Schmitz
      1927 Jan. 25. -- 1 item from E. Robert Schmitz to Concerts Pasdeloup
    - Concerts Populaires (Box 3, Folder 55)
      1928 Apr. 17. -- 1 item from Concerts Populaires to E. Robert Schmitz
      1928 May 1. -- 1 item from E. Robert Schmitz to Concerts Populaires
      Typed letter(copy) from Concerts Populaires to Bottenheim marked "copy for Robert" laid in
    - Concerts "Pro Arte" (Box 3, Folder 56)
      1926 Apr.-May. -- 4 items from Concerts...
      1926 Apr.-Sep. -- 7 items from E. Robert Schmitz
      5 documents laid in, which include copies of letters from the Belgian ambassador to the Département des Affaires Étrangères, from Mrs. Arthur Reis to Ambassador Cartier, and to Bogue
    - Connor, Frank H.
    - Connor, Kathleen
    - Conservatoire de Musique et d'Art Dramatique (Montréal)
      See: Champagne, Claude
    - Cook, J.D.
      See: Opera and Concert
    - Coolidge, Elizabeth Sprague, 1864-1953 (Box 3, Folder 57)
      1937-1945. -- 1 item from Coolidge
      1937-1945. -- 4 items from E. Robert Schmitz
      See also: VII. SCHMITZ SCHOOL OF PIANO AND OTHER SCHOOLS. A.3. Trust Fund
    - Copland, Aaron, 1900-, 1946 Jan. 3; 2 items. (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Corinaldesi, Francesco Pallotelli, 1927 June 17; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Cory, George C., Jr. (Box 3, Folder 59)
      1949 Aug. 15
      From Cory to Jean Leduc
    - Coulthard, Jean, 1908- (Box 3, Folder 59)
      1947 Dec. 3. -- 2 items from Adams (Enclosure)
      1947 Oct.-Dec. -- 2 items from Monique Leduc
      See also: VII.SCHMITZ SCHOOL OF PIANO AND OTHER SCHOOLS. A.4. North American Prize
    - Crédit Lyonnais
      See: VII.A. FINANCIAL AND LEGAL MATERIAL
    - Curtis Institute of Music, 1946 Oct. 29; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Curwen & Sons Ltd.
      See: J. Curwen & Sons Ltd.
    - Cushing, Charles C.
      See: University of California; and VII. SCHMITZ SCHOOL FOR PIANO AND OTHER SCHOOLS. A.5. Debussy Prize
    - Cuvelier, Mr. ?
      See: Concerts Populaires
    - Damrosch, Walter, 1862-1950 (Box 3, Folder 60)
      1920 Dec. 30. -- 2 items from Damrosch to E. Robert Schmitz
      1922 May-July. -- 3 items from E. Robert Schmitz to Damrosch
    - Dana, Richard H.
      See: Music Press, Inc.
    - Dandelot, A., 1924 Mar.-July; 4 items. (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Davis-Chase, Anita (Box 3, Folder 62)
      1920-1922. -- 6 items from Davis-Chase (Includes expense statements)
      1921-1922. -- 2 items from E. Robert Schmitz
    - Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918, and Emma (Mrs. Claude) (Box 3, Folder 63)
      1913-1914. -- 5 items from the Debussys to E. Robert Schmitz
      1927 Dec. 14. -- 1 item from E. Robert Schmitz to Emma Debussy?
    - Debussy Prize for Pianists
      See: Antheil, George; and VII. SCHMITZ SCHOOL FOR PIANO AND OTHER SCHOOLS. A.5. Debussy Prize
    - Defauw, Désiré, 1885-1960, 1945 Dec. 23; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Delgrange, Félix, 1923 Jan.-Mar.; 2 items. (Box 3, Folder 64)
      typed letter (copy) from E. Robert Schmitz to ? mentioning Delgrange laid in
    - Dello Joio, Norman, 1913-, no date; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Del Purves, Miss, 1948 July 21; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Derjanovsky, Mr. ?, 1928 Nov. 5; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - De Rochemont, Richard, 1946 July 15; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - "Direction de Filarmonia" (Leningrad), 1928 Nov. 5; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Dubois, Theodore, 1837-1924, 1911 Dec. 19; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Duell, Sloan & Pearce, Inc.
      See: Meredith Press
    - Durand, Jacques, 1865-1928 (Box 3, Folder 67)
      1914-1921. -- 8 items from Durand to E. Robert Schmitz
      1921-1922. -- 3 items from E. Robert Schmitz to Durand
      Postal receipt and 2 notes laid in
      See also: VIII.A. FINANCIAL AND LEGAL MATERIAL. A. Durand & Fils Editeurs
    - Earle, Rosa M. (Box 3, Folder 68)
      1930-1931. -- 4 items from Earle and Mary Collett to E. Robert Schmitz
      1930-1932. -- 7 items from E. Robert Schmitz and Germaine Schmitz to Earle and Collett
    - Edison, Thomas A. (Thomas Alva), 1847-1931, and Minna Miller (Mrs. Thomas A.) (Box 3, Folder 69)
      1920 July-Dec. -- 7 items from Edisons and secretary, W.H. Meadowcroft, to E. Robert Schmitz (Includes photocopy)
      1920 June-Aug. -- 7 items from E. Robert Schmitz to Edison (Notes laid in)
      See also: Kodály, Zoltán; and Ravel, Maurice
    - Eichheim, Henry, 1870-1942, 1929 July 31; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 70)
      From K. Yamamoto, Managing Director of the Imperial Theatre, Tokyo, to Eichheim - with note on top of first page from Eichheim to E. Robert Schmitz
    - Elkan, Henri
      See: Elkan-Vogel Co., Inc.
    - Elkan-Vogel Co., Inc. (Box 3, Folder 71)
      1941-1946. -- 13 items from Elkan...
      1945-1946. -- 9 items from E. Robert Schmitz and Monique Leduc
    - Enesco, Georges, 1881-1955, postmarked 1913 Mar.; 2 items. (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - English, Harold, 1948 Apr. 27; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 73)
      From William Heusinkveld, Secretary
    - Etude, 1946 Dec. 7; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Falla, Manuel de, 1876-1946 (Box 3, Folder 74)
      1914-1931. -- 14 items from Falla and Ledesma to E. Robert Schmitz (Includes 2 photocopies)
      [1920?]-1931. -- 8 items from E. Robert Schmitz to Falla
      1924 May 19. -- 1 item typed letter from E. Robert Schmitz to Salzedo laid in
      no date. -- 1 item typed letter from Salzedo and Varèse to Falla laid in
      See also: Salzedo, Carlos; and Varèse, Edgar
    - Fauré, Gabriel, 1845-1924, no year Oct. 10; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - Fassett, James H.
      See: Columbia Broadcasting System, Inc.
    - Feit, Claire
      See: National Concert and Artist Corporation
    - Filharmonja Kierownictwo Koncertów Symfonicznych
      See: Cbojnaelej?
    - Fischer, Walter
    - Fiset, Gene (Box 3, Folder 76)
      1946-1948. -- 1 item from E. Robert Schmitz and Monique Leduc
      See also: VII. SCHMITZ SCHOOL OF PIANO. A.3. Trust Fund and 4. North American Prize
    - Fishbein, Arthur L.
      See: Klein, Sigmund
    - Fisher, Marjory M.
      See: VII. SCHMITZ SCHOOL OF PIANO AND OTHER SCHOOLS. A.5. Debussy Prize
    - Fitelberg, Gregor
    - Fitzgerald, Larry
      See: National and Concert Artist Corporation
    - Fleming, Agnes
    - Fleming, Robert J.B. (Box 3, Folder 76)
      1946 Nov. 22. -- 1 item from Fleming to Monique Leduc
      1946 Dec. 3. -- 1 item from Monique Leduc to Fleming
    - Foreign & International Book Company, Inc. (Box 3, Folder 76)
      1947 June 7. -- 2 items from Foreign... (Enclosure)
      1947 June 2-13. -- 2 items from Monique Leduc
    - Forsee, Mrs. George
      See: Pro-Musica (Kansas City Chapter)
    - France. Ambassador (U.S.)
      See: Bonnet, Henri
    - France. Consul Général (San Francisco)
      See: Bertrand, Raoul
    - France. Consulat Général (N.Y.) (Box 3, Folder 77)
      1925-1928. -- 3 items from Consulat to E. Robert Schmitz
      1928 Sep. 15. -- 1 item from E. Robert Schmitz to Consulat
    - France. Délégation du Gouvernement Provisoire de la Republique Française (U.S.), 1944 July 13; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - France. Ministère des Affaires Étrangères, 1928 July 19; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - France. Ministère de l'Instruction Publique et des Beaux Arts (Box 3, Folder 78)
      1918-1928. -- 20 items from Beaux Arts to E. Robert Schmitz
      Copy of letter from Brussels to Monsieur Mongendre and [6] sheets with information about E. Robert Schmitz's health and military service laid in
      1921-1923. -- 8 items from E. Robert Schmitz to Beaux Arts
    - France Forever (Box 3, Folder 79)
      1944-1946. -- 3 items from France Forever to E. Robert Schmitz
      Copy of open letter from General De Gaulle laid in
    - France Libre (Box 3, Folder 79)
      1944 July 31. -- 1 item from France Libre to E. Robert Schmitz
      1944 Nov. 29. -- 1 item from E. Robert Schmitz to Tuteur
    - Frankenstein, Alfred Victor, 1906- (Box 3, Folder 80)
      1947-1950. -- 2 items from Frankenstein to Monique Leduc
      1947-1950. -- 3 items from Monique Leduc to Frankenstein
    - Free Library of Philadelphia. Edwin A. Fleischer Music Collection, 1951 July 13-25; 3 items. (Box 3, Folder 80)
      From the Library
      Postal receipt laid in
    - Frohlich, Richard F.
      See: American Society of Composers, Authors, and Publishers
    - Fuchs, Joseph
      See: Tibbett, Lawrence
    - G. Ricordi & Co.
      See: Hauser, Arthur A.
    - Gaines, Arthur
    - Galaxy Music Corporation (Box 3, Folder 81)
      1947 Sep. 4. -- 1 item from Galaxy
      1947 Sep. 10. -- 1 item from Shirley Jones
    - Gallino, Luigi (Box 3, Folder 81)
      1926-1927. -- 2 items from Gallino
      1927 Apr.-May. -- 2 items from E. Robert Schmitz
    - Garden, Mary, 1877-1967, 1920 Jan. 15; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - Gaubert, Philippe, 1879-1941 (Box 3, Folder 83)
      1920 July 3. -- 1 item from Gaubert to E. Robert Schmitz
      1922 Jan. 28. -- 2 items from E. Robert Schmitz to Gaubert
    - Gédalge, André, 1856-1926 (Box 3, Folder 84)
      1922-1927. -- 4 items from Gédalge to E. Robert Schmitz
      1922 Dec. 3. -- 2 items from E. Robert Schmitz to Gédalge
    - Geiger, Mrs. L. Porter, 1948 Dec. 22; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - Geiger, Robert C.
    - General Anilene & Film Corporation. Ozalid Products Division (Box 4, Folder 85)
      1941 Apr.-June. -- 4 items from Ozalid
      1941 July 5. -- 1 item from E. Robert Schmitz
      1941 Apr. 29. -- 1 item from F.W. von Meister to Mr. R.C. Wentworth of Langlois & Wentworth (Payment stub laid in)
    - Georgescu, [George?], 1930 Mar. 22; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - Gilmore, Arthur (Box 4, Folder 87)
      1931 July 2. -- 1 item from Gilmore
      1930-1931. -- 2 items from E. Robert Schmitz
    - Golschmann, Vladimir, 1893-1972, 1924-1951; 25 items. (Box 4, Folder 88)
      Typed letter (copy), clipping, and flier enclosed
    - Goossens, Eugene, Sir, 1893-1962 (Box 4, Folder 89)
      1932-1936. -- 7 items from Goossens (Sheet with pencil notes by Goossens laid in)
      1933-1936. -- 8 items from E. Robert Schmitz (Enclosure)
    - Goossens, Janet
      See: Barraud, Henry
    - Grainger, Percy, 1882-1961, 1919-1928; 3 items. (Box 4, Folder 90)
    - Green, Jeanette
    - Greene, Gloria, 1948 July 21; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 90)
    - Haas, Alexander E.
      See: Music League of America, Inc.; and National Concert and Artists Corporation
    - Haensel & Jones
    - Hahn, Franco (Box 4, Folder 91)
      1927 Apr. 6. -- 1 item from Hahn
    - Hammond, Emily (Mrs. John Henry), no year May 8; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 91)
      Card with note laid in
    - Hanson, Howard, 1896- (Box 4, Folder 92)
      1925-1945. -- 8 items from Hanson to E. Robert Schmitz (typed letter (copy) from Hanson to Mr. Klein laid in)
      1925-1926. -- 4 items from E. Robert Schmitz to Hanson
    - Hardy, Helen V. (Mrs. Charles S.) (Box 4, Folder 93)
      no year Mar. 4. -- 1 item from Hardy
      1922 July 29. -- 2 items from E. Robert Schmitz
    - Harlam, H. Grady
      See: VI.A. WRITINGS... "Musical Accuracy"
    - Harris, Richmond
    - Harris, Roy, 1898-, 1946 Jan. 3; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - Harsányi, Tibor (Box 4, Folder 94)
      1931 Apr.-Dec. -- 7 items from Harsányi to E. Robert Schmitz
      1931 Mar.-Dec. -- 5 items from E. Robert Schmitz (Postal receipt laid in)
    - Haubiel, Charles, 1892-1978 (Box 4, Folder 95)
      1947 Jan. 13. -- 1 item from Haubiel to Monique Leduc
      1947 Jan. 19. -- 1 item from Monique Leduc to Haubiel
    - Hauser, Arthur A. (Box 4, Folder 95)
      1948 Jan. 6. -- 1 item from Hauser
      1947 Dec. 29. -- 1 item from E. Robert Schmitz
      See also: Carl Fischer, Inc.
    - Havemeyer, Mary, 1947 Sep. 23; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 95)
      See also: VII. SCHMITZ SCHOOL OF PIANO AND OTHER SCHOOLS. A.3. Trust Fund and 5. Debussy Prize
      Hearst, Siegfried
    - Heidelberg, Jack, 1948 May 7; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 95)
    - Heifetz, Jasha, 1901-
    - Held, Rose A.
      See: Schola Cantorum of New York
    - Henderson, Dorothy C. (Box 4, Folder 95)
      1945-[1947]. -- 3 items from Henderson
      1945-1948. -- 6 items from E. Robert Schmitz and Monique Leduc
      See also: VII. SCHMITZ SCHOOL OF PIANO AND OTHER SCHOOLS. A.3. Trust Fund, 4. North American Prize, and 5. Debussy Prize
    - Henriot, Nicole, 1925-, 1953 Jan. 26; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 96)
    - Hertz, Alfred (Box 4, Folder 97)
      1924-1927. -- 5 items from Hertz
      1924-1927. -- 7 items from E. Robert Schmitz and Bernard Laberge
    - Heugel, 1921 Mar.-Apr.; 2 items. (Box 4, Folder 98)
    - Heusinkveld, William
      See: English, Harold
    - Hoérée, Arthur (Box 4, Folder 99)
      1928 July-Nov. -- 4 items from Hoérée
      1928-1930. -- 3 items from E. Robert Schmitz
    - Holmes, Mrs. Christian R., 1932 May 15; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 99)
    - Honegger, Arthur, 1892-1955 (Box 4; 29, Folder 100; 3)
      1916-1929. -- 10 items from Honegger
      1927-1929. -- 7 items from E. Robert Schmitz
      Also laid in: questionnaire filled out by Honegger; 2page list of programs for Honegger's appearances at Pro-Musica chapters; sheet with program for Honegger tour; 2 page agreement for Honegger tour between Pro-Musica and Bogue-Laberge; typescript sheet with Honegger account; typescript list of suggested Honegger programs; a ticket for a performance of Les Aventures du Roi Pausole (1930-1931); and a clipping with a brief biography of Honegger
    - Hood College
      See: Naitonal Concert and Artists Corporation
    - Horner-Witte Concert Bureau, Inc. (Box 4, Folder 101)
      1926 July-Nov. -- 4 items from Horner...
      1926 July-Dec. -- 5 items from E. Robert Schmitz
      Also laid in: typed letter (copy) from Horner-Witte to Bogue-Laberge, 1927 Aug. 13; 2 TLs (copies) from Bogue-Laberge to Horner-Witte, 1927 July-Aug.; and a torn portion of a contract with financial notes on back
    - Hugo Heller & Cie., 1924 Apr. 28-29; 2 items. (Box 4, Folder 102)
      2 receipts
    - Hull, Cordell, 1871-1955, 1939 Oct. 3; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 102)
    - Huré, Jean, 1877-1930, no date; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 102)
    - Hurok, Solomon, 1888-1974, 1938 Sep. 22; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 102)
    - Illingsworth, Elsie
    - Imperial Theatre (Tokyo)
      See: Eichheim, Henry
    - Inch, Herbert (Box 4, Folder 103)
      1946 Nov. 27. -- 1 item from Inch
      1946 Dec. 5. -- 1 item from E. Robert Schmitz
    - Indy, Vincent d', 1851-1931, 1922-1928; 9 items. (Box 4, Folder 104)
      Includes photographic negative of an autograph letter signed, a photograph, and an autograph letter signed (photocopy)
    - Ives, Charles, 1874-1954, and Harmony T. (Box 4, Folder 105)
      1938-1954. -- 11 items from Ives to E. Robert Schmitz and Germaine Schmitz (Includes 2 programs and 4 clippings)
      1926 Dec. 2. -- 1 item from E. Robert Schmitz to Ives
      See also: B. Requests for information from Monique Leduc. Kirkpatrick, John
    - J. Walter Thompson Company
    - J. Curwen & Sons Ltd. (Box 4, Folder 106)
      1927 May 20. -- 1 item from J. Curwen to E. Robert Schmitz
      1926 Feb. 23. -- 1 item from E. Robert Schmitz to J. Curwen
    - J. Walter Thompson
    - Japan Pro-Musica Center
      See: Pro-Music Center Japan
    - Jean-Aubrey, G., 1926 May 14; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 107)
      To Germaine Schmitz care of Ravel, see also: Ravel, Maurice
    - Jobin, Raoul, no date; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 107)
    - Johnson, Lockrem, 1924-1977 (Box 4, Folder 107)
      1946-1947. -- 2 items from Johnson
      1946-1947. -- 3 items from Monique Leduc
    - Johnson, Thor (Box 4, Folder 108)
      1948 Aug. 3. -- 1 item from Johnson
      1948 July 28. -- 1 item from E. Robert Schmitz
    - Jordan Hall
      See: Davis-Chase, Anita
    - Judson, Arthur, 1881-1975 (Box 4, Folder 109)
      1927 Oct.-Nov. -- 3 items from Judson
      1927 Nov. 9. -- 1 item from E. Robert Schmitz
      1927 May 20. -- 1 item from Laberge
    - Kahn, Erminie, 1947 Aug. 18; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 110)
    - Keller, Hermine (Box 4, Folder 110)
      1949 Nov. 8. -- 1 item from Keller
      1949 Nov. 15. -- 1 item from Monique Leduc
    - Kieckhoefer, Marie
    - Kindsring?, no date; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 110)
      Expense statement
    - Klein, Sigmund (Box 4, Folder 110)
      1931 Feb.-May. -- 2 items from Klein
      1931 Mar.-June. -- 4 items from E. Robert Schmitz
      Includes E. Robert Schmitz typed reply on telegram from Klein and an enclosure
      See also: Pro-Musica (Detroit Chapter); and Thomasset, Charles A.
    - Knox, Helen, 1926 Dec. 4; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 110)
    - Knuth, William
      See: San Francisco State College
    - Kodály, Zoltán, 1882-1967 (Box 4, Folder 111)
      1922-1924. -- 3 items from Kodály to E. Robert Schmitz
      1923-1926. -- 12 items from E. Robert Schmitz to Kodály, Edison Co., and to and from Victor Talking Machine Company
      Clipping enclosed
      See also: Edison, Thomas A.
    - Kohn, Bernard A.
    - Koos, Dr. G. de (Box 4, Folder 112)
      1931 Sep.-Dec. -- 4 items from de Koos
      1930-1932. -- 9 items from E. Robert Schmitz
      Laid in: typed letter (copy) from NBC Artist Services to de Koos; and a list of works for piano and orchestra in E. Robert Schmitz's repertoire
    - Korngold, Erich Wolfgang, 1897-1957, 1947 Sep. 3; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 113)
    - Koussevitzky, Serge, 1874-1951 (Box 4, Folder 114)
      1946 Aug. 8. -- 2 items from Koussevitzky to E. Robert Schmitz
      1926 Apr. 28. -- 1 item from E. Robert Schmitz to Koussevitzky
    - Kramer, A. Walter
      See: Galaxy Music Corporation
    - Krenek, Ernst, 1900- (Box 4, Folder 115)
      1947 June-Sep. -- 3 items from Krenek to Shirley Jones
      1947 Sep.-Oct. -- 2 items from Monique Leduc and Shirley Jones
    - Krueger, Karl, 1894-, 1948 Jun.-Dec.; 2 items. (Box 4, Folder 116)
    - Kurtz, Efrem, 1900-, 1946 Jan. 5; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 117)
    - Laberge, Bernard R.
      See: Brussel, Robert; Judson, Arthur; Pro-Musica (Chicago Chapter); Ravel, Maurice; and Tansman, Alexandre
    - Labunski, Felix, 1892-1979, no date; 2 items. (Box 5, Folder 118)
      Brochure enclosed
    - Lang, Malcolm, 1927 Oct. 30; 1 item. (Box 5, Folder 118)
    - Langlois & Wentworth
      See: General Anilene & Film Corporation. Ozalid Procucts Division
    - Lapham, Roger D. (Box 5, Folder 118)
      1946 Apr. 2. -- 1 item from Lapham
      1946 Apr. 1. -- 1 item from Monique Leduc
    - Larson, M.
    - Lawrence, Marjorie, 1947 Jan. 16; 1 item. (Box 5, Folder 119)
    - Leduc, Jean
      See: United States. Veterans Administration (San Francisco)
    - Leduc, Paul
      See: Canadian Broadcasting Corporation
    - Leeds Music Corporation, 1946-1947; 3 items. (Box 5, Folder 119)
      Contract laid in (1946 Mar. 26)
    - Leonard, J. Paul
    - Lert, Richard, 1945 Dec. 26; 1 item. (Box 5, Folder 119)
      Levine, Marks
    - Lévi-Strauss, Claude (Box 5, Folder 120)
      1945-1947. -- 6 items from Lévi-Strauss (Includes typed letter signed, 1946 Jan. 14 (copy))
      1946-1947. -- 4 items from E. Robert Schmitz
      See also: France Forever
    - Liceo Musicale G. Verdi
      See: Gallino, Luigi
    - Lilienthal, Joseph, 1927 Nov. 17-21; 2 items. (Box 5, Folder 121)
    - Linden, Eugene, 1946-1947; 3 items. (Box 5, Folder 121)
    - Ling, Louis
      See: Pro-Musica (Detroit Chapter)
    - Lloyd, Geoff H.
      See: Pro-Musica (Honolulu Chapter)
    - Look
      See: Armitage, Merle
    - Louis Ferdinand, Prince de Bavière, 1912 May 18; 1 item. (Box 29)
      With: typed letter signed from Alphonse, Prince de Bavière
    - Lyceum Theatre (Shanghai)
      See: Paci, Mavis
    - Lyon, Robert, 1927 Jan. 15; 1 item. (Box 5, Folder 121)
    - M. Baron Company
      See: Baron, Maurice
    - McCoy, Mrs. Theo
    - MacDonald, Robert
      See: Pro-Musica (Chicago Chapter)
    - MacDowell, Marian, 1857-1956, no year Apr. 24; 2 items. (Box 5, Folder 122)
      Flier enclosed
    - MacMillan, Ernest, Sir, 1893-1973, 1945-1946; 2 items. (Box 5, Folder 123)
    - McNeal, Katherine (Box 5, Folder 124)
      1922 Nov. 6. -- 1 item from McNeal
      1922 June 1. -- 1 item from E. Robert Schmitz
      Laid in: typed letters signed Selby C. Oppenheimer and from Sherman, Clay & Co., both date 1921 Aug. 3; and financial statement for lecture-recitals - St. Francis - Sep.-Oct. 1921
    - McPhail School
      See: Schoettle, Elmar and Gustav
    - McVay, Mary (Box 5, Folder 124)
      1930 June 7. -- 1 item from McVay
      1930 June 10. -- 1 item from E. Robert Schmitz
      2 copies
    - Major Press, Inc.
    - Malipiero, Gian Francesco, 1882-1973, 1925 Jan. 29; 1 item. (Box 5, Folder 125)
    - Manziarly, A. de (Box 5, Folder 125)
      1946 Mar. 12. -- 1 item from Manziarly
      1946 Apr. 2. -- 1 item from E. Robert Schmitz
    - Mariotte, A. (Box 5, Folder 126)
      1922 Apr.-Nov. -- 9 items from Mariotte
      1922 June-Sep. -- 3 items from E. Robert Schmitz
    - Markevitch, Igor, 1912-1983, 1938 Mar. 27; 4 items. (Box 5, Folder 127)
      3 brochures laid in
    - Markiewicz, Henryk (Box 5, Folder 128)
      1930-1931. -- 2 items from Markiewicz
      1928-1931. -- 3 items from E. Robert Schmitz
    - Martenot, Ginette, 1902-, no year Sep. 12; 1 item. (Box 5, Folder 129)
    - Martenot, Maurice, 1898-1980 (Box 5, Folder 129)
      1929 Oct. 23. -- 1 item from Martenot to Germaine Schmitz
      1929 Sep.-Dec. -- 2 items from Germaine Schmitz to Martenot
    - Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912, 1911 Oct. 17; 3 items. (Box 5, Folder 130)
      Card and envelope laid in
    - Mathews, Ann C.
    - Mathieu, Edgar (Box 5, Folder 131)
      1929-1930. -- 4 items from Mathieu
      1929-1930. -- 2 items from E. Robert Schmitz
    - Mayer, Daniel
      See: Ravel, Maurice
    - Mengelberg, Willem, 1871-1951 (Box 5, Folder 132)
      1928 Apr.-May. -- 2 items from Mengelberg to E. Robert Schmitz
      1928-1930. -- 3 items from E. Robert Schmitz to Mengelberg
    - Meredith Press, 1960-[1961]; 2 items. (Box 5, Folder 133)
      3 royalty statements laid in (1959-1965)
    - Messager, André, 1853-1929, 1913 Oct. 30; 1 item. (Box 5, Folder 134)
      From Messager to Florent Schmitt
    - Milhaud, Darius, 1897-1974 (Box 5, Folder 135)
      1922-[1956?]. -- 16 items from Milhaud to E. Robert Schmitz and Germaine Schmitz (Includes 2 autograph letters signed (photocopies only))
      1922-1929. -- 9 items from E. Robert Schmitz
      Also laid in: 3 programs (1940- 1956); 2 sheets with jottings in E. Robert Schmitz's hand; 2 sheets about Milhaud tour; and a clipping (1989)
    - Miller, Averil (Box 5, Folder 136)
      no date. -- 2 items from Miller to Joyce Kozloff
      1932 Apr.-May. -- 3 items from Joyce Kozloff